so this is the state of the processor we
have some instructions fetch this is the
very first one that we will be trying to
issue this is our reservation stations
our register file with the values the
rat that says where the values are
currently and it's pointing to the
register file for now the Rob that is
empty for now this is the little table
that we will be writing uh what happens
in which cycle and then this is kind of
the legend for our reservation stations
and drops because we need to know which
field to put which value in so in cycle
one what's going to happen is we're
going to try to issue this first
instruction to do that we need an
available reservation station and an
available Rob entry we have both so we
are ready to go it's a divide and we're
going to write the divides kind of
operation here it's writing to R2 so
we're going to note that in the
destination register over here we're
going to write the destination tag in
the reservation station that's going to
be Rob one now remember that the value
we broadcast the result with basically
the tag that everybody's trying to
compare is now going to be the Rob entry
number not the reservation station
number that's what allows us to free
reservation stations very quickly the R3
and R4 are going to be looked up here we
will find that it's 45 and 5 and write
it here and then we're going to rename
R2 so that it points to Rob one from now
on and then because we said that we will
be able to dispatch in the very same
cycle and begin execution in the next
cycle we have issued this instruction in
cycle one
it's going to begin executing in cycle
two because both of its operants have
values ready to go now in cycle two this
instruction begins executing so the
reservation station becomes free before
I free the reservation station I'm going
to note that this instruction is
dividing 45 and five so the result that
is going to eventually end up in the Rob
is going to be 9 45 over 5 this
instruction is not done so technically
this value lands here only when it's
done but I'm going to know this is
what's going to happen because I want to
know what that value will be and with
that this reservation station becomes
free so now it's going to happen this is
a divide it's going to take 40 Cycles to
do things so in cycle 42 which is the
41st Cycles since we began executing we
try to write its result that's going to
be a long time in the future meanwhile
in cycle two we're going to try to do
the rest of the things can we dispatch
something else well nothing to dispatch
can we issue something well the
multiplication has a reservation station
and Rob entry ready to be obtained so we
can do that it's a mile of R1 the tag
for it is now going to be Rob two R5 and
R six are three and four so we have the
values we don't have to wait for
anything and R1 is our result now we
need to remember that R1 from now one is
mapped to Rob two basically if anybody
from now on wants to use R1 it really
needs to wait for the result of uh
instruction in Rob to so this
instruction has issued in cycle two it's
going to dispatch also in cycle two
because it's ready to go so in cycle
three it's going to begin executing and
with that we have moved to cycle three